Mary Schofield papers, 1862-1992 M0428
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
Mary Schofield papers,
1862-1992
M0428
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
19.0 Linear feet (7.5 manuscript boxes, 2 cartons, 8 flat boxes)
Correspondence about the Children's Literature collection. Walter Crane letter with drawing to W.A.S. Benson, 1889. Paper dolls, drawings, posters, puzzles, figurines, and ephemera relating to the Schofield children's literature collection. Also included are early family correspondence, photographs, and documents.
Potter, Beatrix
Schofield, Mary L.
Acquisition Information
This collection was in part purchased (1981) with subsequent gifts from Mary Schofield (1987, 1991-1992) and Carol Jacobs (1996) to Stanford University, Special Collections.
Scope and Contents
The collection has been minimally processed and listed at folder or item level for artifacts.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Crane, Walter, 1845-1915; Ludbrook, Susan; Schofield, Mary L.; Tudor, Tasha; Children's literature
- Old Mother Hubbard, original sketchbook (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Genlis correspondence, Sept. 15, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Photograph: Civil War image of James B. Nickerson, Mary Schofield's maternal grandfather (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Nickerson correspondence, 1964-1877 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Civil War correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photograph: Mary Schofield's mother (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters to Mary Schofield (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lobby Cards:photographs (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Catalogues,order forms,mat. about Potter (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Serials (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Potter (Box 2, Folder 6)
- articles, newsclippings (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Beatrix Potter; publications (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Crane Walter letter, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Sandstone and Tile (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Misc. serials and publications (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Friends of Mary L. Schofield collection (Box 3, Folder 3)
- History of childrens literature (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Schofield correspondence,incoming (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Mary Schofield receipts (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Schofield correspondence,incoming (Box 3, Folder 7)
- High School diplomas/ Stanford commencement (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Schofield correspondence,incoming (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
- Evenings with Colorado Poets (Box 3, Folder 11)
- La literatura en los paises latino americanos (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Mary Schofield correspondence, from the children's book council Inc. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Schofield correspondence from Caroline Laughton (Box 4, Folder 3)
- History 137 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Schofield correspondence,incoming (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
- Schofield misc.: photographs, stanford diploma, Stanford ephemera (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Schofield correspondence re. Children's books (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Schofield correspondence (Germany) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- "Impressions of the European Sanatoria" (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Official land Grant [photocopy], 1838 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Misc. book catalogs (Box 4, Folder 13-16)
- Beatrix Potter exhibit material (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Discharge certificate 1865 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Mary Schofield biography (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Announcements,programs (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Fyleman Rose TLS, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Exhibits,libraries,special events,agendas,programs (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Collection info./ biographical info. Schofield (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Schofield Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Advent calendar (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Paperdoll cutouts (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- The tales of Beatrix Potter,1977 Calendar (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Beatrix Potter Calendar 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- A 'Peter Rabit' Tray cloth (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, from Susan Lodbrook (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Blank cards (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Benjamin Bunny, miniature figurines, Mother Goose, Jemima Puddleduck, Mrs. Rabbit, Mr. Benjamin Bunny, Peter Rabit (Box 7)
- Fragile: Plate, hot plate, Timmy Willie, Lady Mouse, old Mr. Brown, eggshaped porcelain tinket box, Squirrel Nutkin (2), Little Pig Robinson, Sir Issac Newton, Miss Moppet, Mr. Jeremy Fisher (Box 8)
- Fragile: Portrait of two rabbit heads, Portrait of two rabbits walking, Portrait of 3 rabbits, Portrait of bunnies (5 bunnies) (Box 9)
- child's bib, "The Land of Beatrix Potter" fabric - Beatrix Potter tea towel (Box 10)
- Rolling panorama with music box, 2 scrolls (Box 11)
- Fragile: framed item - deer and a man with a bouquet of flowers, framed item- boy, framed item - girls (2), framed item - baby sleeping, framed item - little girl putting something in her ear (Box 12)
- Scroll bible and key (Box 13)
- Victorian scrapbook(2), incomplete puzzle pieces, little framed items, blocks (Box 14)
- Benjamin Bunny puzzle (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Roly-Poly pudding puzzle (Box 15, Folder 2)
- original embossed design, Paul Reyaund (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Various newspaper articles (Box 15, Folder 4)
- old french children's pictures (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Cora Blanca (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Image of a farm (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Betty Bonnet #35 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Postcard (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Le Chat Botte image (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Disneyland (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Old fashioned embossed Bunny rabbit & friends (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Cut outs & costumes (Box 15, Folder 13)
- picture of girl; Thomas Handforth (Box 15, Folder 14)
- The first lesson (Box 15, Folder 15)
- le cachet, le chat, et le souriceau, fable CVIII (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Drawing of a man (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Beatrix Potter centenary(2) (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Flier for motion picture (Box 15, Folder 19)
- 6 colour portraits of Beatrix Potter (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Scrap of frog (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Peter Rabbit and other tales; poster (Box 15, Folder 22)
- matted illustrations(2) (Box 15, Folder 23)
- count Pocci, proof illustrations (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Illustrations by Muff (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Children's letters to Mary Schofield regarding exhibit (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Various illusrtations (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Newspaper articles (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Guest book Jan. 4, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Guest book Dec. 5, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Postcards (Box 16, Folder 7)
- H.C. Andersoin silluettes (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Illustrations (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Vie Champetre Paisible (Box 16, Folder 10)
- "she stood at the door and begged for a piece of Barley-corn" (Box 16, Folder 11)
- A woman and a man kissing (Box 16, Folder 12)
- The tinkerbox (Box 16, Folder 13)
- unused folder (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Edmund Dulac exhibition (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Tolv Med Poster (Box 16, Folder 16)
- A picture of a woman with papers on the floor (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Mermaid and a man (Box 16, Folder 18)
- The mermaid (Box 17)
- Empty children's suitcase (Box 18)